不
No!
我得走了
I gotta go.
我也是
Me, too.
罪案现场见  性感女神
I'll see you at the scene, sexy.
好
Okay.
哈维尔·埃斯波西托
Javier Esposito.
到了现场  别冲我抛媚眼
When we get to this crime scene, do not wink at me,
不要对我笑
do not smile at me,
也别楚楚可怜地看我
and don't even look at me with those
明白吗
puppy dog eyes. Got it?
明白
Got it.
吉娜  得了吧
Come on, Gina.
我不要再和你讨论这个话题了
I'm not having this conversation with you again.
我挂了  我在做正事呢
Well, I'm--I gotta go. I'm at work.
真的是正事
It is so work.
怎么了 卡塞尔  什么事
What's up, Castle? How's it going?
给你个忠告
You want my advice?
千万别和自己的同事搞在一起
Never sleep with someone you work with.
什么  你什么意思
What? What do you mean?
相信我  不会有好结果的
Trust me. It doesn't end well.
谁说的
Who knows?
大家都这么说
Everyone knows.
大家都说什么
Everyone knows what?
没什么
Nothing.
马上就来
On my way.
没事吧  卡塞尔  郁郁寡欢的
You okay, Castle? You seem upset.
没  没事  我很好  怎么了
No, no, I'm fine. Why?
没什么
Okay.
凶案竟然发生在德雷克魔术店
The murder is here at Drake's magic shop?
对
Yep.
我从13岁开始就老来这里
I've been coming here since I was 13 years old.
这里就是男孩子的天堂
This place is a paradise for boys--
这有放屁坐垫  魔术把戏  假呕吐物
Whoopee cushions, magic tricks, fake vomit.
不只是男孩子的天堂  卡塞尔
It's not just for boys, Castle.
我祖父是个业余魔术师
My grandfather was an amateur magician,
我十几岁的时候
and I used to come here almost every Sunday afternoon
几乎每个周末下午都来这
when I was that age, too.
从没想过你也会痴迷魔术
I never pegged you for a magic fan.
有什么拿手的把戏
You know any good tricks?
我有一个拿手把戏
I do this one thing
卡塞尔的扮演者曾在记者会上用冰块搞笑
详情请google"castle icecube"
就是大变冰块
with ice cubes.
从死者身上浸水的钱包来看
According to his water-soaked wallet,
死者是店主扎尔曼·德雷克
the victim's Zalman Drake, the shop owner.
早晨他的助手伊莱扎·温特开店时
His assistant, Eliza Winter, found him in the tank
在水箱里发现了他
when she opened up the store this morning.
有没有任何强行进入的痕迹
Any signs of forced entry?
-没有  -知道吗  我很难理解
- No. - You know, it is beyond me
为什么大家会觉得这很有意思
why people think this is entertaining.
我看到的只是一个倒挂在水箱里的人
I see a guy hanging upside down in a water tank,
我觉得这很愚蠢
I think, you are a fool.
这些奶罐和水刑箱
Hmm. See the milk cans and the water torture tank,
它们的出现真正改变了整个魔术界
they were real game changers in the magic world.
它们首次呈现了
They were the first presentation
现实生活中的生死关联
of real life-and-death consequences.
魔术师停止呼吸的同时
As the magician held his breath,
观众也屏住了呼吸
so did the audience.
但是这位魔术师要想成功谢幕
well, this magician would've had to hold his breath
就要屏住呼吸八到十个小时
eight to ten hours if he wanted to take a bow.
你推测死亡时间是午夜十二点到凌晨两点
So you're saying between 12:00 and 2:00 A.M.?
应该如此
Looks that way,
死者眼睛的淤血显示是溺水死亡
petechial hemorrhaging in his eyes indicate drowning.
难道是逃跑失败
Failed escape attempt?
死者倒挂的脚踝处
Well, there's no redness around his ankles
没有淤血
where he was hanging.
说明他没有挣扎逃脱
Doesn't look like he struggled to get out.
我推测他在入水之前就已死亡
I have a feeling he was dead before he hit the water,
但是需要回实验室做进一步确认检查
but I won't know for sure until I get him back to the lab.
也许他没有挣扎另有原因
Maybe there's another reason he didn't struggle.
一张自杀留言
Suicide note.
说他陷入财务危机
It says he was in financial trouble
不忍看到家传老店丧失其手
and couldn't bear the thought of losing his family's shop,
所以自杀
so he was gonna kill himself.
德雷克先生不是自杀的
Mr Drake did not kill himself.
-你怎么知道  -我就是知道
- How do you know? - I just know.
那他的店要破产  这是真的吗
Is it true, though? Was he gonna lose his shop?
不是
No.
我是说  是的
I mean, yes,
但是两周前  他告诉我
but two weeks ago, he told me
一切都很顺利
that everything was fine,
他都已经解决了
that he had worked it all out.
知道怎么解决的吗
Any idea how?
意外之财  还是有人赞助
Was there a windfall or an investor?
他没说
He didn't say.
他之前能自己倒挂在那个水箱里吗
Would he have been able to place himself in that tank?
完全没问题
Absolutely.
但是他不会这么做  扎尔曼不会
But he wouldn't have. Not Zalman.
他太热爱魔术  太尊敬魔术了
He loved and respected magic too much.
埃斯波西托  这没有签名
Esposito, there's no signature here.
我让鉴证组检测一下指纹
I'll have C.S.U. run it for prints.
让他们把水箱还有入口和出口也查一下
Have them run the tank and the entries and exits as well.
是
Okay.
你最后一次见到他是什么时候
When was the last time you saw him?
昨天上午  他吃完午饭就离开了
Yesterday morning. He left right after lunch,
之后就再也没见到过他
and he was gone the rest of the day.
他有说他要去哪吗
Did he say where he was going?
他平时也会在
Was it normal for him to leave
中午离开店里吗
the shop in the middle of the day?
是的  有时候会
Yeah. He would do that sometimes.
你有没有发现他有什么异常举动
Did you notice any changes in his behavior
或者生活中有什么和往常不一样的吗
or anything unusual going on in his life?
上个月  他经常离开店里
This past month, he was gone m-more often.
他只是说  他正在处理一些事情
All he'd say was that he was working on something.
但他看起来有点累  好像根本没有休息
But he looked a little tired, like he hadn't been sleeping.
知道为什么会这样吗
Can you think of any reason for the change?
是的  上个月  在所有这些发生之前
Yes. Last month, right before all this started,
一个男子来到店里  打了德雷克先生
a guy came into the shop and attacked Mr. Drake.
把他推倒  砸破了表演箱
He pushed him right through a display case.
那个人警告他最好小心点
He said he better watch his back,
因为他会想尽办法起诉德雷克先生
and he was gonna sue him for all he was worth.
谢谢  我等您消息
Thank you. I will hold.
法院记录显示一个月前
So court records show that
确实有一场针对扎尔曼·德雷克的诉讼案
a lawsuit was filed against Zalman Drake a month ago.
他们现在正在查  嘿
They're pulling it up now. Hey.
嘿  我们检查了魔术店周围的区域
Hey. We canvassed the area around the magic shop.
一名邻居说在半夜她看到
One of the neighbors said she saw an old white van
一辆白色的旧汽车停在店旁
pull up to the shop around midnight
然后听到大门打开的声音
and then heard the gate roll up.
好  你们去查一下
Okay, you guys look into that,
看看扎尔曼到底去了哪里
and let's find out where Zalman was disappearing to.
我要知道在他死之前的这段时间
I'd like to know what he was doing
他都做了什么
all the way up until the moment that he died.
有什么近亲吗
What about his next of kin?
唯一的亲属是在波基普西的哥哥
Only surviving relative's a brother in Poughkeepsie.
-我们还没联系到他  -好了  谢谢
- We haven't reached him yet. - All right, thank you, guys.
波基普西
Poughkeepsie?
x射线眼镜  在魔术店买的
X-ray specs. Got 'em at the magic shop.
我能看到你的裸体
I can see you naked.
是吗
Really?
喜欢我的脐环吗
How do you like my navel ring?
好像有人有自己的小秘密了
Looks like somebody has a secret.
秘密  什么秘密
A secret? Uh, what secret?
我能理解有些事情是不想和别人分享的
I can understand a guy not wanting to share.
我是说  有些事情确实很私人
I mean, some things are personal.
你怎么发现的
How did you find out?
伙计  地球人都知道了
Dude, everybody knows.
占了第六版整个版面
It's all over "Page six."
"出版商和神秘作家
"Looks like an unhappy ending for
将不欢而散"
the publisher and the mystery writer."
很明显
Apparently,
他和吉娜  这位前妻加前女友加出版商
he and ex-wife/girlfriend/ publisher Gina
在"马戏团"餐厅吵架了  大吵了一架
had some words--loud words-- at le cirque,
吉娜大发雷霆
and she stormed off.
原来上午他谈的就是这事
That's what he was talking about this morning.
我不理解的是  为什么他想要
What I don't understand is why he would try
瞒着我们  我是说
to hide it from us. I mean,
我们就像是一家人一样
we're like family.
也许他在意别人的看法
Maybe he's afraid of what we might think.
扎尔曼·德雷克确实曾经面临一场官司
So it turns out a lawsuit was filed against Zalman Drake
原告叫做杰罗姆·阿斯彭纳
by a Jerome Aspenall.
再听听这个
And get this--
法官昨天驳回了他的上诉
the judge threw it out yesterday.
也许杰罗姆决定自己替天行道了
Maybe Jerome decided to take justice into his own hands.
因为何事起诉被害人
What was he suing him for?
扎尔曼·德雷克  我告他诽谤
Zalman Drake? I was suing him for slander,
毁损名誉  毁掉了我的生活
defamation of character, ruining my life.
杰罗姆  扎尔曼做了什么
And how did Zalman do that, Jerome?
他他妈的读懂了我的想法
He read my friggin' mind,
当着300个人的面
In front of, like, 300 people.
表演魔术吗
During a magic performance?
是啊  在奇奇慈善舞会
Yeah. It was like this mind reading,
有读心术  纸牌戏法  飘浮表演之类的
card tricks, levitation, at this ChiChi charity ball.
我的岳父岳母赢得了一桌席位
My in-laws won a table,
我就想  免费的食物  娱乐节目
and I figured, free food, some entertainment,
说不定还能中大奖  结果刚好相反
maybe later, I get lucky. Turns out not so lucky.
-你能详细说说吗  -当然
- Could you elaborate on that? - Yeah,
这个魔术师  扎尔曼·德雷克上了台
this magician, Zalman Drake, gets onstage,
把一个有钱人变没了  又变出来了
makes this rich dude disappear and reappear,
我就想"挺酷啊"
and I'm like, "Oh, that's cool."
之后他邀请志愿者上台  我妻子举起了我的手
Then he asks for volunteers. My wife raises my hand
说"上去玩玩  很有趣的"  于是我上台了  德雷克说
and says "Go up there, it'll be fun," So I do. Drake says,
"站在我对面  想一些好事"  我就想了
"Stand across from me and think good thoughts," So I do.
他看着我  集中注意力
He looks at me, concentrates,
把手放到我额头
puts his fingers on my forehead,
他说"你在想
and he goes, "You're thinking
上周末和芮塔去亚特兰大城的事"
of Rita and your trip to Atlantic City last weekend."
你在想那件事吗
Were you?
是的  但是我竭力不去想
Yeah, but I was trying not to,
-因为最倒霉的是  -你的老婆不叫芮塔
- 'cause here's the kicker-- - Your wife's name isn't rita.
是的
Right.
现在我住在长岛的小旅馆里
So now I'm living in a motel in long island city,
岳父解雇了我  芮塔也不愿跟我说话
my father-in-law fired me, and Rita won't even talk to me
因为我老婆找到了她的电话  跟她通了话
'cause my wife found her number and called her.
你昨晚12点到2点在哪
Where were you last night between 12:00 and 2:00?
她为什么问我这个问题
Why is she asking me that?
-她想知道你是否有不在场证明  -什么不在场证明
- Well, she wants to know if you have an alibi. - For what?
扎尔曼·德雷克昨晚被谋杀了
Zalman Drake was murdered last night.
正义得到伸张
Justice is served.
在他做读心术的时候  用了很长时间吗
When he read your mind, did it take him very long?
-不  没有  -不是吗
- No, he--no. No. - Didn't think so.
杰罗姆  我们有证人证明你去过他的商店
Jerome, we have a witness who says you went to his shop,
袭击并恐吓了扎尔曼·德雷克
attacked, and threatened Zalman Drake.
当他们昨天驳回你的上诉时
When they dropped your lawsuit yesterday,
你是不是决定自己伸张正义
did you decide to take the law into your own hands?
你是不是去了魔术用品店  谋杀了扎尔曼
Did you go to the magic shop and murder Zalman?
不  我昨晚哪都没去
No, I didn't go anywhere last night
我只去了57街和第七街交口的奥拉汉酒吧
except for O'Lannahan's at 57th and seventh,
因为被那个扎尔曼·德雷克害的  我赔了夫人
because thanks to Zalman Drake, I no longer have a wife
又折了情妇
or a mistress to go home to.
我想知道扎尔曼是怎么做到的
Wonder how Zalman did it.
他肯定是从杰罗姆的口袋里拿出了
He must have lifted something from Jerome's pocket
证明他出轨的收据之类的
with a receipt from his weekend of sin.
这样吗
Like this?
你的手伸进了我的口袋  我却没有感觉到
You had your hand in my pocket, and I didn't even feel it?
再来一次
Do it again.
怎么了
What?
莱恩
Hey, Ryan.
找到扎尔曼昨天
Any luck narrowing down Zalman's
去了什么地方吗
whereabouts yesterday?
没有
Uh, not yet,
但是我查了杰罗姆昨晚的去处
but I did check into Jerome's whereabouts last night.
奥拉汉酒吧的酒保说
The barkeeper at O'lannahan's said
他一直待到关门才走
he was there till closing.
他给他叫了出租车
He called him a cab.
这么说他昨晚唯一杀死的就是脑细胞
So the only thing he killed last night were his brain cells.
另外  鉴证组在水箱和器具上
And a forensic sweep of the water tank came up negative
也没有找到
for any prints on the operating
除了扎尔曼以外的任何指纹
apparatus other than Zalman's.
所以要么他是自杀
So either he committed suicide...
要么杀手戴了手套
Or the killer wore gloves.
没有一直戴着  根据报告
Not the whole time. According to the lab,
遗书上都是指纹
there were fingerprints all over that suicide note,
既不是扎尔曼也不是杰罗姆的指纹
and they weren't Zalman's or Jerome's.
找到匹配记录吗
Did you get a match?
是啊  查尔斯·查克·拉塞尔
Yeah, to a Charles "Chuck" Russell.
一个落魄的街头魔术师
A low-life street magician
三次被捕  两次定罪
with three arrests and two convictions--
一次因为纵火  另一次
One for arson and another on
-因为爆炸指控  -他认识被害人吗
- an explosives charge. - Did he know our victim?
是的  扎尔曼是美国魔术师协会里
Yeah, apparently Zalman is some big muckety-muck
很重要的人物
with the American Magicians Guild.
他们有自己的行规
They have a code of professional conduct,
查克打破了规矩
and Chuck broke it.
他对于表演中的烟火表演非常不计后果
He was reckless with pyrotechnics in his act,
弄伤了他的助理  扎尔曼把他踢出协会
injured his assistant, so Zalman had him kicked out.
从那之后他一直没能签到大的演出机会
He hasn't been able to book a gig since.
在哪能找到他
Where can we find him?
我手里拿着布兰达的手表
So I have Brenda's watch here.
她想让我把他的丈夫消失
She wants me to make her husband disappear.
那是重罪  我不能那样做
That's a felony. I can't do that.
但是我可以把这块表弄没
But I can make the watch disappear.
来点掌声
Give it up.
谢谢你  布兰达
Thank you, Brenda.
哎哟  一美元
Aw. $1.
我今晚去拉曼餐厅吃饭  给小费的时候会想着你的
I'll dine on Raman and tap water tonight and think of you.
你呢  你有什么捐给
What about you? You got a little something
美国魔术师大学基金会吗
for the United Magicians College Fund?
事实上  我有
As a matter of fact, I do.
我们要跟你谈谈扎尔曼·德雷克
We need to talk to you about Zalman Drake.
阿布拉卡达布拉[表演魔术时的咒语]
Abracadabra.
阿拉卡赞姆[同为咒语]  混球
Alakazam, jackass.
翻译：东方  大卫熊  末末  千花  小蛮腰  深深  小池
时间轴：Jimmy贝壳   后期：瓜瓜   校对&总监：安小七
干嘛把我带到这里
Why am I here?
认出这个了吗
You recognize this?
那是一个袋子装着一封信
That's a baggie and that's a letter.
下个问题
Next.
小心点  小查  下个问题就是谋杀指控了
Careful, Chucky. Next could be a murder charge.
-你的指纹在这封信上  -那又如何
- Your fingerprints are on it. - So?
我觉得在别人的遗书上
So I find it strange that someone else's fingerprints
找到其他人的指纹非常奇怪
are on another guy's suicide note.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你的老朋友扎尔曼·德雷克
Your old friend Zalman Drake.
扎尔曼
Zalman?
是啊  就是他
Yeah, that's him.
他自杀了吗
He killed himself?
-天呐  -我们发现
- Man. - We found him drowned
他淹死在他商店的水刑箱里
in the water torture trick in his shop.
你肯定觉得自己很聪明吧
You must have thought you were pretty clever,
把一切弄得像是拙劣的逃生术一样
staging it to look like a botched escape.
我什么都没弄  跟我没关系
I didn't stage anything. I had nothing to do with it.
那你解释一下为什么你的指纹在这上面
Well, then maybe you can explain your prints on that.
好吧
All right.
等等  好吧  听着  我给了他这张条
No, wait. Okay, listen, I-I-I gave him this note.
你给了他这遗言
You gave him a suicide note?
不是这个
Not that note.
是纸上另外一张条  你看不见的那条
The other note on the paper. The one you can't see.
在紫外光灯下看看
Hold it under a black light.
是服务的报酬清单
It's an invoice for services rendered.
什么服务
What kind of services?
他想让我帮他找到一样东西
He wanted me to get him something,
非法的东西
Something illegal.
C4炸药
C4 explosives?
很讽刺  是吧
Ironic, right?
他想从我这要炸药
He wants explosives from me
而正是因为炸药他把我踢出协会
when that's what he got me booted for.
但是他保证让我重新入会
but he promised to get me reinstated in the guild,
-我迫切想找到工作  -不管是谁
- and I wanted to work. - Whoever wrote this note
写的这张遗言肯定以为是拿了张白纸
probably thought they took a blank piece of paper.
反正那个人不是我
Whoever being not me.
你给他提供的炸药
You provided him with enough c4
足够炸掉半个街区了
to blow up half a city block.
-干什么用  -也许是魔术表演用
- What was it for? - Maybe it was for a magic trick.
得了吧
Come on.
听着  扎尔曼不仅仅是经营商店
Nah, listen, Zalman didn't just run the shop
做做商业表演
and do corporate gigs.
他也是个天才的魔术设计师
He was also this genius trick designer.
有传言说  他为如今最红的魔术师
Rumor has it, he was creating
打造了表演用的最尖端的魔术
cutting-edge illusions for the hottest guy out there.
谁是最红的魔术师
And who is the hottest guy out there?
图比斯·斯瑞奇  他可是魔术界的约翰尼·戴普
Tobias Strange? He's the Johnny Depp of magic.
我在维加斯看过他表演  他把法拉利变没了
I saw him in Vegas. He made a Ferrari disappear.
-怎么会有人干那种事  -是啊
- Why would anybody want to do that? - Yeah,
他在这儿  我两周前还看过他的表演
He's in town. I saw him perform a couple of weeks ago.
棒极了  精彩绝伦啊
Awesome, awesome show.
我们都很喜欢
Yeah, we loved it.
我们
We?
是啊
Yeah.
我和我哥们儿
Me and my buddy.
-阿雷  -你有个叫阿雷的哥们儿
- Ray.  - You have a buddy named Ray
还跟他一起去看魔术表演
who you went with to a magic show?
-是啊  有问题吗  -好了  伙计们
- Yeah. What about it?  - Okay, guys,
以贩运爆炸物罪继续拘留查克
Hold Chuck on an explosives trafficking charge,
看看这个魔术界的
and let's see if this "Johnny Depp
约翰尼·德普是否知道
of magic" knows what his
他的魔术设计师到底在搞什么鬼
trick designer was really into
又为何需要这么多的C-4
and why it required so much C-4.
好了
Voila.
拉紧了
Pull it tight.
继续
All the way.
要锁好了
Make sure it's locked.
好了  各位  30秒计时
Okay, guys, 30 seconds,
现在开始
starting now.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
哦  天哪
Oh, my god!
快打开
Oh! Get it open!
你怎么样了
Are you OK?
到里面看看
Get in there
-他人呢  -嘿  现在是私人排演时间
- Where is he?  - Hey, this is a private rehearsal.
是谁让他进来的
Who the hell let them in here?!
通行证在此
All-access pass.
自继承了他爸爸的店子以来
Zalman has been the heart
扎尔曼一直都是
of the New York magic community
纽约魔术协会的核心成员
since he inherited the shop from his dad.
这可是个巨大的损失
It's a huge loss.
我知道他在为你做事
I understand that he worked for you.
以前是  但上个月我们分道扬镳了
He used to. We parted ways last month.
-为什么  -我听一个卖家说
-Why?  - I heard from one of my vendors
他可能还在替别人做事
that he might be working for someone else,
于是就去质问他  结果发现  他被挖走了
so I confronted him. Turns out, he was poached.
-知道是被谁挖走的吗  -他没说
- Do you know by whom?  - He didn't say.
扎尔曼做我的
Look, Zalman had been
专用设计师和工程师已经15年了
my exclusive designer and engineer for 15 years.
他创造了几个我最著名的魔术
He created some of my most famous tricks.
如果有机会上台演出的话
If he had any stage presence,
他会成为一个世界一流的魔术师
he would've been a world-class magician himself.
这么多年后  他的离开
Well, it must have been very upsetting
肯定是一件让人很心痛的事
to have him leave after all those years.
这样一来你那些小秘密岂不是有被暴露的危险
Didn't that put some of your trade secrets at risk?
卡塞尔先生  你这是在暗暗指控我呢
A thinly veiled accusation, Mr. Castle.
我当然心痛了
Of course I was upset.
但我从没怀疑过他行事谨慎的作风
But I never doubted his discretion.
斯瑞奇先生  你有没有哪些魔术
Mr. Strange, did any of your illusions
需要借助爆炸物的呢
require the use of an explosive?
"雾中幻境"一词
The term "Smoke and mirrors"
在我们这一行里可不是说着好听的  警探
isn't metaphoric in our business, detective.
很多错觉都是由光影造成的
Much of misdirection depends on flashes of light.
是否要用到C-4呢
What about C-4?
使事情看起来很危险的关键
The key to making something look dangerous
就是要牢牢掌控道具的效果
is to have complete control over the outcome.
C-4太不稳定了  无法把握
C-4 is too volatile, unpredictable.
它会造成伤亡
It kills.
知道扎尔曼会用它来干什么吗
Any idea what Zalman would be using it for?
肯定和魔术无关  我敢保证
Nothing magical, I assure you.
你们检查过他的工作室没
Have you checked his workshop?
我们没发现有工作室
Uh, we haven't come across a workshop.
有可能他离开店铺后就是去了那儿
It's probably where he'd been disappearing to every day.
你知道在哪儿吗
Do you know where it is?
你们应该知道魔术师对隐私都很保密的
You know how magicians are about secrets.
但至于他到底在干什么
But whatever he was working on,
你们在那儿应该能找到答案
you would probably find there.
这故事太老套了
It's an age-old story--
一个顶级魔术师
Magician at the top of his game,
因其魔术设计师
angry that his trick designer
跳槽投入对手怀抱而怀恨在心
has jumped ship for the competition,
因此杀了他
kills him instead of
以防他泄漏秘密到敌人手里
letting his trade secrets fall into enemy hands.
这是魔术  卡塞尔  又不是冷战
It's magic, Castle, not the Cold War.
既然不是冷战
Well, if it's not the Cold War,
那扎尔曼要
why does Zalman need
-军用爆炸物品干嘛呢  -我怎么知道
- military-grade explosives?  - I don't know. Hell.
我们甚至不知道他是否真的是被谋杀的
We don't even know if it really was murder.
据我们所了解的来看  有可能还真是自杀
For all we know, it could've actually been a suicide.
-是蕾妮  -我猜猜  不是自杀
- It's Lanie. Let me guess.  - It wasn't a suicide.
你们这速度都快赶上乌龟了
It took you two long enough.
到哪儿去了  欧洲吗
Where were you, Europe?
-堵车  -孩子  干嘛不用警灯呢
- Traffic.  - Girl, you could've used the gumball.
盛装打扮  而且很急切
Dressed to the nines, in a big hurry.
说说  要去哪儿  那幸运的倒霉蛋是谁
So... Where are you going and who's the lucky victim?
行啊  卡塞尔
I'll tell you what, Castle,
你先说说你和吉娜之间是怎么回事
you tell me what's going on between you and Gina,
我再告诉你我要去哪儿
and I'll tell you where I'm going tonight.
你们在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
他和女友在餐厅大吵了一架
He and his girlfriend had a big fight at le cirque.
都上报了
It was in the paper.
请说说那个被害者好吗
Can we talk about the victim, please?
好吧
Okay.
肺部没有积水
No water in the lungs.
他不是淹死的
He wasn't drowned?
不是  是窒息而死的
Nope, but he was asphyxiated,
这两者有时症状很相似
which sometimes presents the same way.
有瘀伤
Bruising.
像是有人用手压着他的鼻子和嘴
Like someone held their hand over his nose and mouth.
在被放入水箱前他就被杀死了
He was murdered before he was put into the tank.
然后凶手拿了一张
And then his killer took what he thought
他以为是空白的纸  打了自杀说明
was a blank piece of paper and typed out the suicide note.
但为什么要用这种方法呢
But why kill him that way?
我是说  为什么要弄的像自杀一样
I mean, why make it look like a suicide?
掩饰凶手
Cover up the murder.
是凶手呢  还是涉及爆炸物的
The murder, or something bigger
更大的阴谋
involving explosives?
我们必须找到那个工作室
We gotta find that workshop.
你们俩还真是文明夜生活的楷模啊
You are the picture of a civilized evening at home.
而你就是个山顶洞人
And you are a caveman.
亲爱的  我们可是你的家人
Darling, we are your family.
你怎么不告诉我们这件事呢
Why didn't you tell us about this?
你有和她联系过吗  自那次公众事件以来
Have you spoken to her, you know, since your P.D.A.?
-那次  -当众泄愤
- My--  - Public display of anger.
上面说你们在吵架  爸爸  吵什么
It says you were fighting, dad. What about?
-好吧  你们一定要知道的话  -没错
- Well, if you must know...  - Yes.
我们在争吵这么多年我们到底吵了多少架
We were fighting about how much we've been fighting.
不介意的话  我真的想
If you don't mind, I'd really like
换个话题
to change the subject.
把我当6岁小孩呢
What am I, 6?
至少也变出个20美元啊
At least pull out a $20.
-嘿  我在想  -快  卡塞尔  跟上
- Hey, I was thinking--  - Come on, Castle. Keep up.
-这是要去哪儿  -扎尔曼的工作室
- Where are we going?  - Zalman's workshop.
你找到啦  怎么找到的
You found it? How?
在他浸水的钱包里有张浸水的地铁卡
In his soggy wallet was a soggy metrocard.
莱恩查了自动收费数据库
Ryan ran it through the automated fare database.
他往来于魔术用品店附近的地铁站
He was traveling from a subway stop near his magic shop
和布朗克斯区的终点站之间
to the last stop out in the Bronx.
所以我们要去那周围调查
So we're canvassing the neighborhood.
-要穿防弹衣吗  -不  不用
- Do we need vests?  - No, no vests.
记得两星期前的停电事件吗
Remember that power outage a couple of weeks ago,
-地铁也停了  -记得
- shut down the subway? - Yes.
我查了下扎尔曼的财务报表
Well, I looked into Zalman's financials.
那天他用信用卡雇了辆车
He hired a town car that day with his credit card,
我们已经把地址搞到手了
and we now have his address.
你确定是这里吗
You sure this is the place?
他是在这儿下车的
This is where they dropped him off.
这里像是块荒地  被围起来了
Well, it looks abandoned, bricked up.
快看  快看
Look, look, look.
有脚印
Footprints.
看到了  然后就凭空消失了
Yes, to nowhere.
这正是他留给我们的难题
That's what he wanted us to think.
芝麻开门
Open sesame.
扎尔曼的世外桃源
Zalman's fortress of solitude.
哇  卡塞尔
Wow, Castle.
这地方真对我祖父的胃口
My grandfather would've loved this place.
瞧  他居然有断头台
Look, he has a guillotine.
还有铁娘子
And an iron maiden.
甚至有百折箱
He even had a zig zag box.
知道吗  你和我祖父应该挺投缘
You know, you would've liked my grandfather.
或者说  你让我想起他了
In fact, you remind me of him a little.
荣幸之至
I'm flattered.
轮椅的压痕
Wheelchair tracks?
没错  看上去是最近的
Yeah, and they look fairly fresh.
也许他有访客前来
Maybe he had a visitor.
说得对
Yeah.
都是新弄上的
They look recent.
这些纸上的日期正是他被害的那天
These papers are dated the day he was killed.
我得让鉴证组彻查一下这里
I'm gonna have to get C.S.U. to sweep this whole place.
这是意外  还是某种艺术
Is this an accident or art?
卡塞尔  来看这个
Castle, take a look at this.
有几页被撕掉了
The pages are ripped,
看来他不想
Like he didn't want anyone
别人知道他在干嘛
to know what he was working on.
扎尔曼
Zalman?
你们又是谁
Who the hell are you?
史上最佳魔术
Best trick ever.
纽约警察  把手放在我能看到的地方
NYPD. Keep your hands where I can see them.
怎么回事  你们在这儿干吗
What--what's going on? What are you doing here?
扎尔曼
Zalman?
我是埃德蒙  埃德蒙·德雷克
Edmund. Edmund Drake.
你是他在波基普西的哥哥
His brother from Poughkeepsie?
-你们是双胞胎  -对
- You're a twin. - Yeah.
-我手能放下来了吗  -可以
- Can I put my hands down? - Uh, yeah.
你怎么藏在铁娘子里
Why were you hiding in the iron maiden?
这是隔壁的入口
It's the entrance from the other room.
我是贝克特探长  我们为你弟弟而来
I'm detective Beckett. We're here about your brother.
我也是  他在哪儿
So am I. Where is he?
你还不知道
You don't know?
德雷克先生  很遗憾地通知你
Mr. Drake, I'm sorry to tell you,
你的弟弟已经去世了
but your brother is dead.
不是开玩笑吧
Are you kidding me?
他有个和他一模一样的四眼孪生兄弟
He has an identical twin who wears glasses.
这是继克拉克·肯特后最糟的伪装
That's the worst disguise since Clark Kent,
你居然相信他
and you believe him?
我没理由不信他  你看他完全不知所措
I have no reason not to. Look at him. He's devastated.
都是演戏  难道你从来不看电影吗
It's an act. Don't you ever go to movies?
这...
It's...
很可能死者其实是埃德蒙
It's probably Edmund who's dead,
而隔壁那个傻帽才是扎尔曼
And that dweeb in the next room is Zalman.
我敢打赌他杀害他哥哥  想过上哥哥的生活
I bet he killed his brother to take over his life.
到波基浦西去做会计吗
As an accountant in Poughkeepsie?
呃...这个...
Well, I...
几天前他打电话给我
I knew something was wrong
我就知道出问题了
when he called me a couple of days ago.
他找你做什么
What did he call about?
钱
Money.
他说有人给了他五十万美金
He said someone was paying him a half a million dollars,
-想让我帮他藏匿  -为什么要藏
- and he needed my help to hide it. - Hide it how?
确保政府无法查出
To make sure that the government never found out
这笔钱的来源
where it came from.
他当时的口气让我感到
The way he was talking, it sounded like
他可能扯进什么违法的勾当了
he'd gotten involved in something illegal.
那你在他仓库里做什么
And what were you doing at his warehouse?
我昨天突然觉得
Well, I just had this feeling yesterday
有事情不对头
that something was terribly wrong,
我试图联系他  但是联系不上
and when I tried to reach him, I couldn't.
所以就开车来这儿  这是双胞胎的心灵感应
I drove down to the city. I think it was the twin thing.
我们长这么大  常常有这种情况出现
You know, all our lives, we've had this connection.
当然了  双胞胎的心灵感应
Yeah, of course. The twin thing.
德雷克先生  跟我说说
Tell me, Mr. Drake,
凭你的家学渊源
given your legacy,
为什么你没和他一起继承家业呢
why didn't you ever get into the family business, too?
我没那个激情  当然  也没那本事
No, I didn't have the passion... or the skill.
扎尔曼和我
Zalman and I, we, uh,
我们以前倒是同台演出过
we did have an act together as kids.
他从台上消失
He would disappear up on stage,
我从观众身后消失
And then--then I would appear in the back of the audience.
也许这种把戏
I guess it was only amazing
只能让不知道我们是双胞胎的人叫好
to people who didn't know we were twins.
你太谦虚了
Well, you're being modest.
我确信你们骗过了不少人
I'm sure you fooled a lot of people.
德雷克先生  刚才你说你弟弟牵扯某事
Mr. Drake, the activities that your brother was involved in,
如果让你看看他的东西
if you looked through his things, do you think
不知道你能不能猜出他在做什么
that you would be able to determine what he was doing?
扎尔曼是非常有才华的工程师
Zalman was a brilliant engineer,
凭我的脑子恐怕无法参透他的想法
And, uh, I'm afraid my brain just doesn't work that way.
他是个很特别的人  你懂么
He was someone special, you know?
家族之光
Light up a room.
探长  我不知道他到底在做什么
Look, Detective, I don't know what he got mixed up in.
但我确信他罪不至死
But I just know, he didn't deserve to die.
我简直不敢相信你就这样让他走了
I can't believe you're letting him just walk out of here.
-要在电影里...  -这才不是电影
- If this was a movie... - It's not a movie,
再说我以什么罪名起诉他
and what am I supposed to charge him with,
就因为他是双胞胎吗
Being a twin?
涉嫌一宗魔术谋杀案的恶魔双胞胎哥哥
Being an evil twin in a magic murder.
帮他弟弟藏匿五十万
A half-a-million-dollar payment that he's hiding
躲避政府监督  用以购买塑胶炸药
from the government, bricks of C4?
我可不觉得这是魔术
That doesn't sound like magic to me.
鉴证组刚刚完成初步检查
C.S.U. is just finishing their initial sweep.
目前还没有任何迹象
So far we haven't been able to find anything
表明除了图比斯·斯瑞奇
to indicate who Zalman might have been working for
扎尔曼还给谁卖命
other than Tobias Strange,
但鉴证组在工作台上发现了
but C.S.U. did find some trace residue of C4 explosives
炸药残余物
on the workbench.
地上的压痕呢
And what about the tracks?
你判断得没错  的确是轮椅造成的
You were right. They are from a wheelchair.
这种压痕特征明显
The tracks are pretty distinctive.
我们正在取样制成模型
We're running down make and model now.
幸运的话
Yeah, well, with any luck,
扎尔曼这位客户"神秘教授"即将现身
professor x will turn out to be Zalman's mystery client.
明白  谢谢
Right. Thanks.
这个说法如何  扎尔曼一时头脑发热
What about this? Zalman gets in over his head,
把他哥哥引到这里
He lures his brother down here,
闷死了他  把他放到水箱里
suffocates him, sticks him in a tank
造成他自己死亡的假象
so it looks like he's dead.
然后扎尔曼扮成
Meanwhile, Zalman, as Edmund,
埃德蒙继承魔术店
inherits his own magic shop
收取保险金  与此同时
collects his own insurance, all the while
还能将深爱埃德蒙的妻儿
takes edmund's wife and children,
据为己有
Who love him, as his own.
这不就是"以假乱真"吗
It's "dead ringer."
原来你还在讲话啊
Are you still talking?
埃德蒙即是扎尔曼
Edmund is Zalman.
绝对不可能
Couldn't be more wrong.
我检查了被害人的指纹  确实是扎尔曼
I ran the prints on our victim. He is Zalman.
-满意了吧  卡塞尔  -不如说我很失望
- Satisfied, Castle? - More like disappointed.
或许这能让你高兴点儿
Well, maybe this will cheer you up.
老人的白发
Old man hair.
不  是白色兔毛
White rabbit fur.
从他的牙齿喉咙里发现的
It came from his teeth and throat.
一只誓死不肯
So he was killed by a rabbit
从魔术帽里出来的兔子杀害了他
who did not want to be pulled out of a hat.
你的猜测不比我差嘛
Your guess is as good as mine.
在调查扎尔曼
In the process of trying to determine
窒息原因时
how Zalman was asphyxiated,
我还在他的
I also discovered the presence
鼻子和咽喉处
of a low dose of organophosphates
发现了少量的有机磷酸酯
in his nose and throat.
有机磷酸酯
Organophosphates?
它通常用作液压机液体  飞机引擎润滑油
It's found in hydraulic fluids, jet engine oil,
-杀虫剂  神经毒剂  -神经毒剂
- insecticides, nerve agents. - Nerve agents?
加上之前发现的塑胶炸药
Well, along with the C4,
我们这位魔术师
our magician's sounding
更像是恐怖分子
more like a terrorist.
但含量很低
The amount is too small
说明他并没有直接接触
to indicate that he had been working with them directly,
但最近肯定去过存放这些东西的地方
but he definitely was exposed to them recently.
奥耶  亲爱的  我正好路过这里  就想
Oye, chica. I was in the hood, and I
我们可以顺便聊一聊那个...
thought that we should talk about the--
测试  你让我做的那个
Tests... That you had me run.
化验报告在后面  我去拿
Um, they're in the back. I'll go get 'em.
-好的  谢谢  -什么测试
- Yeah. Thanks. - What tests?
另一个案子  嘿  我刚想打给你
Different case. Hey, I was just about to call you.
记得你在扎尔曼工作室里
You know those wheelchair tracks
发现的那些轮椅痕迹
that you found at Zalman's workshop?
那些锯齿型很独特
Well, they had a sawtooth pattern
只有一家公司为电动轮椅制作这种轮胎
unique to one brand of tire made for electric wheelchairs.
我们打给了六间出售该轮胎的商店
We called the half a dozen specialty shops
并且交叉比对了最近
that stock that tire, and we cross referenced
出售的名单和魔术商店的
recent purchases with the mailing list
-邮寄名单  -找到吻合的吗
- of the magic shop. - Did you get a match?
是的  撒迪厄斯·马格纳斯
Yeah. Thaddeus Magnus.
他是职业反政府示威者
He's a professional government protestor.
因多次非暴力反抗遭逮捕
He's got multiple arrests for civil disobediences,
还有  他开白色货车
and get this-- he drives a white van.
反政府示威者  非暴力反抗
Government protestor, civil disobedience.
再加上c4和神经毒剂
You mix that in with c4 and nerve agent,
-简直是翻版蒂姆·麦克维  -有地址吗
- You're looking at Tim Mcveigh. - You have an address?
-谢了  -嗯
- Thanks. - Mm-hmm.
干得不错
Nice work.
真是惊险啊
That... Was close.
不  这
No. This...
才叫惊/近险
Is close.
一个坐轮椅的人怎么
How does a guy in a wheelchair
将人搬进水箱里
lift someone into a tank of water?
马格纳斯先生  纽约警局  开门
Mr. Magnus, NYPD. Open up.
或者轮椅只是为了掩人耳目
Maybe the wheelchair is an act.
每个魔术秀  都有一个
In every magic story, there's an unexpected twist
出人意料的大转折
where things aren't always what they seem.
是这类表演必须出现的
it's an obligation of the genre.
-什么  -纽约警局
- What? - NYPD.
我们要问你些有关扎尔曼·德雷克的问题
We need to ask you a few questions about Zalman Drake.
德雷克魔术店的扎尔曼·德雷克
Zalman Drake of Drake magic.
时代的终结
End of an era.
我听说他的逃脱术失败了
I hear it was a failed escape.
-更像是一次成功的谋杀  -噢
- More like a successful murder. - Oh?
他被丢进箱子前已经窒息了
He was asphyxiated before he was lowered into the tank.
你是说他真的被谋杀了
You mean he was really murdered?
猜猜他遇害时谁的货车
And guess whose van was spotted outside his shop
正停泊在他店外
right about when he died.
你能别碰那个吗
Would you just not touch that, please?
我花了五年制作的
It took me five years to build it.
他在为你做什么
What was he working on for you?
-那些炸药有什么用  -炸药
- What were the explosives for? - Explosives?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
扎尔曼是我的好友
Look, Zalman was my friend.
他并不替我工作
He didn't work for me.
我为他工作  为他设计的魔术
I worked for him, making specialty items
制作些特别道具
for those tricks he designed.
没有炸药
Nothing explosive.
只是  那样的东西
Just... Well, things like that.
事实是
Doesn't change the fact,
他遇害时你正在店里
you were at his store when he died.
我看起来像是能把他搬进箱子里吗
Does it look like I could've lifted him into a tank?
或许你装了一对假肢
Well, maybe you borrowed a set of legs.
-或者就是这些  -住手
- Maybe these or someone else's. - Stop it.
如果有人杀了他  就是他碰面的那些家伙
If anyone killed him, it was those guys he met.
什么家伙
What guys?
他在替他们工作
The guys he was working for.
他们打电话来的时候我正在仓库
I was there at the warehouse when they called.
我去那里为之前的
I went there to pick up a check
一些工作拿支票
for some work I did on the job.
他们想见他
They wanted to meet him.
告诉他关门后去店里
Told him to go to the store after closing.
扎尔曼叫我载他过去
Zalman... Asked me to drop him off.
接下来  他就死了
Next thing I hear, he's dead.
我不知道他是被谋杀的
I didn't know it was murder.
你在为他做什么
The job that you did for him, what was it?
他让我替他做一个机械手臂
Well, he wanted me to make him a mechanical arm.
用来远程触发一些开关
You know, something to trigger a switch remotely.
理论上  它能触发些什么
Theoretically, what could it trigger?
所有东西  开灯  敲铃
Well, anything-- turn on a light, ring a bell.
设定炸弹
Set off a bomb?
噢  我发誓  我以为他是在开玩笑
Oh, look, I swear, I thought he was joking.
关于什么
About what?
他说这是他最伟大的魔术了
He said this was his greatest magic trick ever.
有人花大笔的钱
Said he was getting paid a fortune
聘请他来帮助逃脱谋杀罪名
to get away with murder.
你真的认为有人会聘请一个魔术师
You really think someone would hire a magician
帮自己逃脱谋杀吗
to help them get away with murder?
这真的很聪明
I mean, it's brilliant really.
魔术师是误导的大师
Magicians are masters at misdirection.
如果他们能操控观众
If they can manipulate audiences,
他们就能控制目击者
they can manipulate witnesses.
他们甚至能让人们
They could even make people testify
为从没发生过的事作证
to things that never happened.
很难相信
It's just so hard to believe
这么尊敬魔术的人
that a person with that much respect for magic
会利用自己的才能去杀人
would use his skills to kill.
他需要保住他的店
He needed to save his shop,
而五十万美元的酬劳也太高了
and a half-a-million-dollar payday was too good to be true.
确实太高  所以他没有拿到  而是丢了性命
And it was. Instead of a payday, he got whacked.
雇他的人大概觉得
Well, the people who hired him probably figured
杀了他会比较安全
it was safer to kill him than run the risk
免得他会受到良心谴责供出他们
of having an attack of conscience and rat them out.
没有证据  我们怎么找到他们
Okay, so without evidence, how are we gonna find 'em?
先找出他们雇扎尔曼去杀的人是谁
By finding out exactly who they hired Zalman to kill.
我们知道他的把戏
We know he was working on a trick
用到了c4和远程触发装置
involving c-4 and a remote triggering device.
他的目标是被炸弹杀死的
Well, whoever he killed went out with a bang.
在最近几周  附近三州地区内
There can't have been that many deaths
因爆炸而死的人
in the tristate area in the last couple of weeks
肯定不会多到哪去
where someone was killed by an explosion.
烟酒枪管局和消防部门的进度怎么样
Where are we with ATF and the fire department?
我们应该能在早上拿到报告
We're supposed to get their reports in the morning.
好的  同时看看我们能查到什么
Okay, meantime, let's see what we can dig up ourselves.
你知道纽约每周发生多少
You know how many explosions there are
爆炸事件吗
in New York city every week?
蒸汽管道爆炸
Steam pipe explodes.
煤气炉爆炸
Gas stove explodes.
情侣间的不满爆发
Unhappy couple explodes.
你不是在餐厅跟那个谁大发脾气吗
Well, didn't you explode in a rather ritzy restaurant
跟
With, uh...
说曹操  曹操就到
Aha. Speak of the devil.
你不打算接电话吗
You're not gonna answer that?
-接什么  -噢  做的不错
- Answer what? - Ooh. Well done.
当然了  令你的电话消失
Of course, making your phone disappear
并不代表问题也消失了
doesn't make your problem disappear.
是啊
No.
嘿  孩子
Hey, come on, kiddo.
你们两个发生什么事了
What's going on with you two, really?
什么事也没有
Nothing's going on.
不  没事  所有事都很好
No, nothing at all. Everything is fine.
所有事都
Everything is...
很好
Just fine.
跟往常一样
It's ordinary.
问题是
The problem is, I...
我不想要一成不变
I don't want ordinary.
我想要
I want--
魔法
Magic.
对  你知道问题是
Yeah. You know what the problem is,
我们不再相爱了
is we just aren't in love.
我们都不想承认
Neither one of us wants to admit...
有机磷酸酯
Organophosphates.
那不是神经毒剂而是喷射机燃油
It wasn't a nerve agent. It was jet oil.
-扎尔曼当时在飞机场  -什么
- Zalman was at an airport. - What? I--
我得走了
I gotta go.
一眨眼就不见人影了
Now you see him, now you don't.
嘿  我知道扎尔曼要杀害的目标了
Hey. I think I figured out who Zalman was paid to kill.
亿万富翁慈善家克里斯琴·达尔
Billionaire philanthropist Christian Dahl?
你怎么也...
How did you...
有机磷酸酯  就是喷气机用油  由此联想到机场
organophosphates, jet oil, airport.
咱俩就像是一对双胞胎
It's like we could be twins.
心有灵犀
Connection.
纯属猜测
Conjecture.
目前我们只知道达尔
All we know right now is that Dahl
周六下午在泰特波罗机场起飞
took off from Teterboro Saturday afternoon
准备刷新自驾机横跨大西洋的飞行速度纪录
intending to set a transatlantic speed record in his jet.
显然后来飞机出了问题
Apparently, something went wrong,
在半空中发生爆炸
and the plane broke up midair.
据长岛海峡一艘油轮上的目击者称
Witnesses out on an oil tanker out on long island sound
他们看到空中闪过白光  飞机冒出浓烟
claim to have seen a white flash and smoke in the sky.
空中爆炸的罪魁祸首
Well, a midair explosion
也许就是扎尔曼从查克那
would account for all the c4 that
买来的全部C4炸药
Zalman bought from Chuck.
还有马格纳斯的遥控引爆装置
And Magnus' remote triggering device.
也许正是想取克里斯琴性命的人
Well, whoever wanted Christian dead
杀了扎尔曼以掩盖罪行
probably killed Zalman to cover up the crime.
但这一切全是我们凭空推测的
Except all we have now is speculation.
喂  我刚和美国联邦航空局通完电话
Yo. I just got off with the F.A.A.
他们把起飞的监控录像发过来了
They're sending over footage of the takeoff.
达尔准备刷新纪录
亿万富翁将飞跃大西洋
就是这  达尔登上了私人喷气机
Okay, there's Dahl getting on his jet
准备做横跨大西洋的飞行尝试
for the transatlantic flight attempt.
看来他正在为起飞作准备
Looks like he's doing his preflight.
看这里
Look at that.
车身图案跟扎尔曼作坊的墙身图案一致
It matches the outline on the wall in Zalman's workshop.
原来他是在墙上漆标
He was painting a decal.
放大那个司机
Zoom in on that guy.
是扎尔曼·德雷克
It's Zalman Drake.
他打扮成餐饮服务商
He dressed like a caterer.
也许他正是借此通过安检的
Probably so he can get past security.
他是去送东西的
He delivered something.
对啊  炸药和引爆装置嘛
Yeah, explosives and a triggering device.
这绝对是雇凶杀人
This was a murder for hire.
快进
Skip ahead.
定格
And freeze it.
他计划让克里斯琴·达尔的飞机
He planned for Christian Dahl's plane
在大西洋上空爆炸
to break up over the atlantic.
堪称完美的犯罪  找不到证据
It's the perfect crime-- no evidence...
-尸体  -和凶手
- No body... - No killer.
你太疯狂了  我从没试过像这样的...
You are crazy. I've never even tried anything like--
-行  好的  我也是  再见  -谁来的
- Yeah. Okay. Yeah, me, too. Bye. - Who was that?
海岸警卫队  我打去看看他们有否
Coast guard. I was just seeing if they, uh,
-找到飞机的数据记录器  -结果呢
- found the plane's data recorder. - Hmm. Did they?
什么结果
Did they what?
喂  两位  克里斯琴·达尔查得怎样了
Hey, guys, where are you on Christian Dahl?
这个人太不可思议了
This guy was unbelievable.
他之所以成为亿万富翁是因为
He became a billionaire by always being exactly
他总能在最佳时机  恰到好处地投资
in the right place at exactly the right time to invest
任何一支即将升值的股票  产品和构思
in whatever stock, product or idea was just about to hit.
那他有仇家
Did he have any enemies,
或威胁过他的人吗
anyone that was threatening him?
没有  我全问过了  人人都爱他
No, all the people I talked to loved him.
他的慈善捐款比奥普拉[美国名嘴]还多
He gave away more money than Oprah,
他还投资了一大笔钱研究玄学
and he gave a lot of money to research into the occult.
他登上过珠穆朗玛峰
He climbed Everest,
乘坐过热气球飞越欧洲
he flew across Europe in a hot air balloon,
他还参加过伊迪塔罗德狗拉雪橇赛
he even drove a dog sled in the iditarod.
既然他那么出类拔萃
Well, with that much going for him,
肯定有一堆仇家的啊
he had to have had a couple of haters.
只有一个  她兼具动机和下手机会
Just one, and she had both motive and opportunity.
内奥米·韦尔登
Naomi Weldon?
内奥米·韦尔登·达尔
Naomi Weldon Dahl--
克里斯琴的妻子  以前是个时装模特
Christian's wife and a former fashion model.
显然一个月前
Apparently, a month ago,
克里斯琴识穿她有婚外情
Christian caught her having an affair,
根据他们的婚前协议  如果男方提出离婚
and according to their prenup, if he divorced her,
女方将一无所得
she wound up with nothing.
但若是他死了  她就能继承所有家产
And if he dies, she inherits billions.
-这张照片是在哪里拍的  -你注意到了啊
- Where was this photo taken? - Ah, you noticed.
六周前的达尔基金效益晚宴
The Dahl foundation benefit six weeks ago.
而当晚的娱乐嘉宾是...
And the entertainment for the evening was...
扎尔曼·德雷克
Zalman Drake.
记得吗  杰罗姆说过
You know, Jerome did say
扎尔曼当晚曾表演过大变活人
Zalman made someone disappear that night.
内奥米看完他的魔术
Naomi sees his performance
心想扎尔曼或许能
and wonders if Zalman can make
让他丈夫永远消失
her husband disappear forever.
反正即将坐拥亿万身家
And with billions on the line...
区区五十万不过是九牛一毛
Half a million's just chump change.
当他们告诉我克里斯琴的飞机失事后
When they told me that Christian's plane disappeared,
我就是这样认为的
that's exactly what I thought.
认为你丈夫的死并非偶然吗
That your husband's death was no accident?
克里斯琴是个完美主义者  人也疑神疑鬼
Christian was a perfectionist, and he was superstitious.
他在娶我之前对我做了三次背景调查
He did three background checks before he married me.
你和你丈夫有一份
You and your husband had
无懈可击的婚前协议
an airtight prenuptial agreement.
这是两个知名人士结婚的标准程序
Standard when two high-profile people marry.
如果你提出离婚或有婚外情
And if you left the marriage or had an affair,
离婚后你将得不到
you'd be leaving the marriage
配偶赡养费或子女抚养费
without spousal or child support.
那就是协议条款
Those were the terms.
我有个人事业  能自食其力
I have my own career. I can take care of myself.
但你确实有外遇
But you were having an affair.
我有没有外遇不归你管
Whether or not I had an affair is none of your affair.
如果你是在暗示我谋杀了亲夫
If you're implying that I murdered my husband
和别人相宿相栖  那你就错了
to be with someone else, you're mistaken.
我才不会杀人
I wouldn't kill anyone.
哪怕能继承巨额遗产吗
Not even to inherit a fortune?
那我就真是自取其辱了
Well, then the joke would be on me.
根本就没有巨额遗产
There is no fortune.
克里斯琴的所有户口都被冻结了
All of Christian's accounts have been frozen.
你是指遗产正在认证中
You mean you're in probate.
-不是  是真的冻结了  -为什么呢
- No, I mean frozen. - Why?
这你得去问地方检察官办公室
You'll have to ask the district attorney's office.
天知道原因是什么  他们不肯告诉我
God knows, they wouldn't tell me.
刚才那是地方检察官
That was the D.A.
显然  在遇难当天
Apparently, at the time of his death,
我们的亿万富翁兼投资大师
our billionaire investment guru
正在接受证监会的调查
was being investigated by the S.E.C.
证监会认为他依靠
They thought that he was making his money
传统诈骗手段来赚钱
the old-fashioned way, by stealing it.
他那些惊人的股票全是伪造的
All of his amazing stock returns were falsified.
整件事根本就是一个庞氏骗局
The whole thing was a ponzi scheme.
原来他们早在几周前就
As it turns out, they were a couple of weeks away from
以巨额欺诈起诉克里斯琴·达尔
indicting Christian Dahl for massive fraud.
他将变得一无所有
He was gonna lose everything
并将在联邦监狱服刑50年
and face 50 years in federal prison.
如果我是他  我也会想人间蒸发
If I were him, I'd want to disappear, too.
而人间蒸发的最佳途径莫过于...
And what better way to disappear...
-雇一名魔术师  -全中
- Than hire a magician? - Bingo.
克里斯琴·达尔正在飞机上做航前检查
Christian Dahl is on the plane doing his preflight check.
扎尔曼离开飞机...
Zalman leaves the plane...
达尔沿跑道滑行并起飞
Dahl taxis to the runway and takes off.
他总得找个时机下机啊
Well, he had to have gotten off at some point,
不然就演变成自杀行动了
Otherwise, it would've been a suicide mission,
自杀可用不着魔术师
and you don't need a magician for that.
除非...
Unless...
机师并不是克里斯琴·达尔
that isn't Christian Dahl.
-看着像是他啊  -假人
- It looks just like him. - Dummy.
不是说你  是说驾驶座上的那个
Not you. The--on-- in the cockpit.
他们将真达尔调包成假达尔了
They switched out real Dahl for dummy Dahl.
马格纳斯做的并不是引爆装置
Magnus didn't build a triggering device for an explosion.
他做的假臂是用来做航前检查的
The arm he built was for doing the preflight check.
那飞机根本就是架自动驾驶飞机
The whole thing's an automaton.
这就是魔术的关键所在
That's the magic trick.
他让全世界以为克里斯琴·达尔
He made it look to the world like Christian Dahl
还在飞机上
was still on the plane,
就跟图比斯·斯瑞奇让人以为
the same way Tobias Strange made it look
他在万剑穿心那刻
like he was still in the cabinet when
人还在箱子里一样
the swords went in.
然后他利用餐车
And then he used the catering box
把假人运上飞机  把克里斯琴·达尔弄下机
to get the dummy on board and Christian Dahl off.
那驾驶飞机的人是谁
Then who's piloting that plane?
克里斯琴·达尔啊  只是并非在驾驶座上控制
Christian Dahl, only not from the cockpit.
他通过遥控器操纵飞机起飞  你看
He had it rigged to fly via remote control. See?
扎尔曼在把餐车搬进小货车
Zalman puts the box in the van.
里头可能有一部控制器
There's probably a console inside there
连着飞机的航空电子设备
linked to the plane's avionics.
达尔遥控飞机起飞
Dahl takes off remotely...
飞到大西洋上空
flies out over the Atlantic...
然后他引爆炸弹
And then he detonates the explosion,
所有人都以为他死了
and everyone thinks that he's dead
因为大家都看到他上了飞机
because everyone's seen him on board.
其实达尔还活得好好的
Only Dahl is very much alive,
而且世界上只有一个人知道他还活着
and there's only one person in the world that knows it.
那就是扎尔曼  只要他还活着  他对达尔来说就是个威胁
Zalman, and as long as he's alive, he's a threat to Dahl.
所以达尔得把这个问题解决掉
So Dahl has to tie up that one loose end.
但是他不能冒险让其他人知道他还活着
But he can't risk anyone knowing that he's still alive.
所以达尔必须亲手杀了扎尔曼
So Dahl has to kill Zalman himself.
怎么了
What?
没什么  那我们现在怎么办
Nothing. So what do we do now?
从事故发生到现在已经四天了
Well, it's four days since the accident.
克里斯琴·达尔没准已经
Christian Dahl is probably
带着一大笔钱
in some non-extradition country
跑到一个没有引渡条款的国家去了
with a chunk of his fortune by now.
没准
Yeah, probably.
除非
Unless...
除非什么
Unless what?
达尔做事喜欢大肆张扬
Well, Dahl does everything publicly.
这家伙喜欢受到万众瞩目  大家都以为他死了
The guy loves being famous. Everyone thinks he's dead.
对于这样一个人来说  不  这主意太疯狂了
A guy like that... No, it's crazy.
卡塞尔  我们现在正需要点疯狂
Castle, crazy is exactly what we need right now.
-卡塞尔  这的确是很疯狂  -疯是疯了点  但是恰到好处
- Castle, this is crazy.  - Crazy but in character.
想想克里斯琴·达尔的做事风格
Look at the kind of guy Christian Dahl was --
他多喜欢成为万众瞩目的焦点
how he loved the limelight,
还有他对死后生活的着迷
his fascination with life after death.
你觉得这样一个人会错过
You think a guy like that is gonna miss the opportunity
参加自己葬礼的机会吗
to attend his own funeral?
-你会吗  -绝不可能
- Would you?  - Not a chance.
好吧  要是他在场的话  我们怎么找到他
Okay, so if he's here, how do we find him?
他肯定会做些伪装
Well, he'll be in disguise, of course.
找一些举止异常的人
Look for an anomaly,
某个想要融入这一切
someone who's trying to fit in
却始终还是格格不入的人
yet sticking to the outskirts,
某个不跟任何人交流
someone who isn't engaging in conversation
但与此同时
but at the same time,
却在一旁偷听别人讲话的人
eavesdropping on other people's conversations.
某个
Someone who's --
留着长头发  小胡子  还穿着一千美金一双的鞋吗
Got long hair, a beard, and $1,000 shoes?
这办法也行
Yeah, that'll work, too.
达尔先生
Mr. Dahl.
既然死了就一直装死嘛  兄弟
You shoulda stayed dead, bro.
我是假造了自己的死亡
So I faked my own death.
那又怎样  这又不是犯罪
So what? That's not a crime.
你们要起诉我什么罪名
What are you gonna charge me with,
污染大西洋吗
littering the Atlantic?
我哪及英国石油公司污染的厉害呀
I'll stand in line behind BP.
罪名是故意谋杀罪
The charge is premeditated murder.
我们看透了你的小把戏
We figured out your little trick.
扎尔曼在你的慈善晚会上演出
Zalman performed for your charity event.
他让你在舞台上消失  于是你灵机一动
He made you disappear, giving you the inspiration
想要借此来永久消失  你知道他缺钱
to pull the ultimate escape. You knew he needed money,
于是你就提出给他一大笔钱
so you made him an offer he couldn't refuse.
但是你根本没打算给他钱  对吧  达尔先生
But you never planned on paying him, did you, Mr. Dahl?
实际上  你计划利用
No, you planned on using his desperation
他害怕丢掉家族遗产的绝望
over the loss of his family's legacy
来使人以为他选择了自杀
to make people think that he committed suicide.
假造枪击太复杂了
Staging a shooting, it's too cumbersome.
会引发太多的问题  像是枪是哪来的
Too many questions. Where'd the gun come from?
所以你就用手头上的资源来除掉
So you used what you had on hand to get rid of
世界上唯一一个知道你还活着的人
the only person on earth who knew you were still alive.
一旦把他除掉  你就自由且永无后患了
Once he was gone, you'd be free and clear.
你们
Is...
你们查案无门的时候就这样吗
is that what you do when you can't solve a crime,
胡编乱造
concoct fantasies?
我们在死者身上找到了
The rabbit hair that lined your gloves
你手套内侧的兔毛
was found on our victim.
你打电话给扎尔曼  约他在他的店里见面
You called Zalman, met him at his shop,
你戴着手套捂住他的嘴
put your gloved hand over his mouth,
然后使他窒息而死
and then you smothered him.
如果你以为我会怕你或是怕证券交易委员会的话
If you think I'm afraid of you or the SEC...
我一定会打得你们哭爹喊娘
I will beat your pants off
然后笑着看你们哭
and enjoy every minute of it...
当然了  前提是我保释出狱后你们还能找的到我
Assuming you can find me once I'm out on bail.
你该害怕的不是我  达尔先生
It's not me that you should be scared of, Mr. Dahl,
也不是证券交易委员会
or the SEC.
你该怕的是你自己现在这个样子
You should be afraid of what you've become.
要是你说教完了
Well, if you're done with your lecture
或是没东西好恐吓我了的话  我想见一下我的
or your petty threats, I'd like to see my...
我的律师
my lawyer.
有什么不妥吗  达尔
Something wrong, Dahl?
没什么
No.
克里斯琴
Christian?
你
H --
你是怎么做到的
How are you doing that?
做到什么
Doing what?
-他见鬼了吗  -我不知道
- Is he having flashbacks?  - I don't know.
你看到他了吗
Do you see him?
谁
Who?
他刚才就在这
He was right here.
天啊
Oh, god.
你不可能  你不可能在这的呀
You can't...you can't be here.
你死了
You're dead!
你已经死了  我
You're dead. I...
我杀了你
I killed you.
阿拉卡赞姆[咒语]  混蛋
Alakazam, jackass.
你怎么知道这招可行
How did you know that would work?
我不知道  我只知道他肯定会叫律师
I didn't. I just knew he'd lawyer up.
所以我想  何不试试呢
So I figured, why not take a shot?
你祖父肯定会为你骄傲的
Your grandfather would be proud.
非常感谢  先生们
Thank you so much, gentlemen.
能帮到纽约警局是我的荣幸
Always a pleasure to lend a hand to the NYPD.
我也许可以把这个加到我的节目单里
I might add this one to my repertoire
来纪念你的哥哥
in tribute to your brother.
谢谢你探长  还有卡塞尔先生
Thank you, detective, Mr. Castle.
那德雷克的魔术店怎么办
So what's gonna happen to Drake's magic shop?
我跟图比斯刚刚正在讨论这个问题呢
Hmm. Tobias and I were discussing that.
扎尔曼拼了命地保护它
Zalman put his life on the line for it,
所以我们希望想个办法保住它
so we'd like to find a way to keep it alive.
也许我们集思广益  能找到解决办法呢
Maybe we can pull a solution out of our collective hats.
晚安
Good night.
再见
Bye.
你能不能
Hey, could you, uh...
没问题
Oh, yeah.
埃斯波西托去哪了
So...where's Esposito?
-大胆猜吧  -找蕾妮去了
- Huh. Take a wild guess.  - Lanie?
你能相信他俩居然还以为我们都不知道吗
Can you believe they still think that none of us know?
让他们继续这样以为一段时间吧
Oh, let's let 'em keep thinking that a while longer.
美好的事物转瞬即逝
The bubble bursts soon enough.
要是找对了人就不会
Not if you're in it with the right person.
-谢谢  -谢谢  再见
- Thanks.  - Thank you. See you.
-失陪一下  我要接个电话  -接吧
- Excuse me. I need to take this.  - Yeah.
不  不
No. No.
我要说的是
What I'm saying is...
咱俩结束了
It's over.
-要走了吗  -是呀  挺晚的了
- Heading out?  - Yeah. It's late.
约了摩托仔吗
Motorcycle boy?
我希望你不要再这样叫他了
I really wish you would stop calling him that.
-摩托仔医生  -他今晚值班
- Dr. Motorcycle Boy.  - He's on shift tonight.
我想看看我能不能来得及吃上一顿怀旧美食
I was gonna see if I could catch the comfort food truck.
你要一起去吗
You want to come?
芝士通心粉  刚出炉的饼干加上热朱古力
Macaroni and cheese, warm biscuits, hot chocolate?
我怎么可能会拒绝
How could I say no?
我想谢谢你
Hey, I wanted to say thanks for, um,
没有提过那篇报道  也没问过我到底发生了什么事
not mentioning that article or asking what was going on.
小事一桩
Not a problem.